Tim Cook: Good morning!
Tim Cook：早上好！
Welcome to Apple Park!
欢迎来到 Apple Park！
We have a huge day of announcements ahead of us,
今天，我们将宣布一些重磅更新
and it's all about iPad.
而主角就是 iPad
In fact, this is the biggest day for iPad since its introduction.
这将是 iPad 诞生以来的一个里程碑
But first I'd like to give you a couple of quick updates.
但首先，我想跟大家分享几个新消息
In February, we shipped Apple Vision Pro.
2 月，我们的 Apple Vision Pro 正式发售
This revolutionary new product is unlike anything that came before it.
这款开创性的新产品堪称史无前例
Now that it's out in the world
现在，它已来到大家身边
and people are experiencing its phenomenal capabilities,
人们开始体验到它的超强功能
we're seeing some amazing things being done with Apple Vision Pro.
也纷纷开始用 Apple Vision Pro 来创造各种精彩
Porsche is building brand-new spatial experiences across the company,
保时捷正在为公司上下打造全新的空间体验
from reimagining track experiences to training service technicians
从赛道体验的全新构思 到维修技师的培训
to creating their showroom of the future.
再到未来展厅的搭建
Dr. Tommy Korn at Sharp HealthCare is using Apple Vision Pro
Sharp HealthCare 的 Tommy Korn 医生 正利用 Apple Vision Pro
to improve surgical eye care
进行模拟、分析和优化
through simulation, analysis, and optimization.
来改善眼科手术的护理
And award-winning film director Jon M. Chu is using Apple Vision Pro
屡获殊荣的电影导演 Jon M. Chu 则戴着 Apple Vision Pro
to oversee the editing and visual effects for his upcoming film "Wicked,"
舒舒服服安坐家中，通过眼前的巨幕
from the comfort of his home, on a giant theater-size screen.
监看他下一部电影 Wicked 的 剪辑和视觉特效
These are just a few examples of the incredible ways
以上只是其中一些示例
Apple Vision Pro is already making an impact in our customers' lives.
让我们看到 Apple Vision Pro 正以各种精彩方式为用户的生活加分
In March, we shipped the amazing new MacBook Air.
3 月，新款 MacBook Air 发售
With the power of M3, it puts even more performance
M3 的强势驱动，让这款超薄超轻的笔电
and capability into the best thin and light laptop.
性能更强，本领更高
Our users are loving it.
用户纷纷点赞
In fact, MacBook Air is now the world's best-selling 13-inch laptop
13 英寸和 15 英寸 MacBook Air
and the world's best-selling 15-inch laptop!
在畅销榜上双双霸榜！
Now let's turn our attention to iPad.
焦点回到 iPad 上
There's no other device like it.
iPad 是如此与众不同
iPad is powerful, portable, and incredibly versatile.
它强大、便携，而且非常多用
In classrooms around the world,
在世界各地的课堂上
iPad is helping students and teachers bring their lessons and learning to life.
iPad 帮助无数老师和学生把学习融进了生活
From architects to engineers,
对建筑师和工程师来说
iPad plays a critical role
iPad 是一款重要利器
in helping them get their most important work done
让他们能以全然一新的方式 搞定各种紧要工作
in entirely new ways, no matter where they are.
无论他们身在何处
For artists, designers, and musicians,
对于艺术家、设计师和音乐家
it provides ways to take their ideas and creativity
iPad 让他们能将创意和创造力
further than ever before.
提升到新的高度
And with its incredible performance,
而得益于超强的性能
powered by Apple silicon and the world's best displays,
Apple 芯片的澎湃动力 以及业内最出色的显示屏
iPad is an amazing device for playing games
iPad 还是休闲和游戏的好伙伴
It's this incredible versatility that defines iPad.
如此出色的多用性让 iPad 自成一派
And today, we have some huge updates across the iPad lineup.
今天，iPad 产品线将迎来一些重大更新
So here's John to tell you more.
有请 John 为大家详解
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
John Ternus: Let's kick things off with iPad Air.
John Ternus：我们先从 iPad Air 说起
iPad Air is designed to deliver advanced features pioneered on iPad Pro,
iPad Air 的设计，是为了将 iPad Pro 率先实现的众多先进功能
and make them available at an even more affordable price.
以更超值的价格带给大家
That's why a wide range of users rely on it to do so many different things.
因此它的用户如此之广 能做的事如此之多
Like college students, who use Goodnotes and Apple Pencil
比如大学生们课里课外都会用到 Goodnotes 和 Apple Pencil
Entrepreneurs who use QuickBooks for their small business
创业者们随时随地通过 5G 用 QuickBooks 处理业务
Creators that rely on the performance of iPad Air and iMovie
创作者们借助 iPad Air 的出色性能
to produce engaging content.
用 iMovie 创作各种精彩内容
And all types of consumers who use it to catch up on a hit show,
更别提各种用户都在用它来追着 Palm Royale 之类的热剧
The combination of a high-resolution display,
高分辨率的屏幕
the phenomenal performance of Apple silicon,
Apple 芯片的超强性能
and its colorful, portable design
亮丽又便携的设计
with support for amazing accessories
以及各种精彩配件
makes iPad Air so versatile for so many.
让 iPad Air 灵活多用，适合各类用户
Well today, we're excited to give all these users
今天，全新的 iPad Air 将让大家的热爱再度升级
And here it is.
请细看
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
For the first time ever, iPad Air comes in two sizes:
iPad Air 将首次推出两种尺寸
a redesigned 11-inch Air,
重新设计的 11 英寸机型
and a spectacular, all-new 13-inch Air.
和醒目的全新 13 英寸机型
And here's Melody to tell you more.
有请 Melody
Melody Kuna: I'm thrilled to tell you all about the new iPad Air.
Melody Kuna： 很高兴为大家详细介绍全新 iPad Air
Let's start with its brilliant Liquid Retina display.
先看看它绚丽的 Liquid 视网膜显示屏
Users love the portability of the 11-inch form factor,
11 英寸机型便携的设计深受用户喜爱
which is perfect for tasks like jotting down notes
比如在做项目时随手记个笔记
while working on a project.
用它就再好不过
Some Air users would prefer an even larger display
有些 iPad Air 用户希望屏幕再大一点
for more room to work, learn, and play.
从而有更多空间来工作、学习或玩乐
So inspired by iPad Pro, where about half the users choose a larger screen,
鉴于 iPad Pro 就有半数用户 选择了更大的屏幕
we created a 13-inch model of the new iPad Air as well.
我们也为新 iPad Air 打造了 13 英寸机型
The 13-inch Air has 30% more screen real estate
13 英寸 iPad Air 的屏幕空间
than the 11-inch Air.
比 11 英寸机型多了 30%
The larger display gives users more space to express their ideas
更大的屏幕让用户在无边记之类的 app 中
in apps like Freeform,
能更尽情地挥洒创意
or to see more participants in a video call on Zoom.
或在 Zoom 视频会议时看到更多参加者
It also provides more space to view multiple apps using Split View in iPadOS.
使用 iPadOS 的分屏浏览时 也有更多空间来查看多个 app
And both displays have the same advanced features.
两款屏幕都拥有同样的先进功能
So all your content looks absolutely gorgeous.
屏上的一切看着都绚丽夺目
We've also redesigned the iPad Air to put the front-facing camera
我们还重新设计了 iPad Air 的前置摄像头
on the landscape edge.
将它横向放置
And it features Center Stage, which uses machine learning
它支持人物居中，能利用机器学习
to automatically keep everyone in the field of view.
自动将所有拍摄对象摆在画面中间
So it's perfect for connecting with friends and family over FaceTime
所以很适合与亲友进行 FaceTime 通话
or joining a video conference while using a keyboard.
或配上键盘用来开视频会议
The new Air features landscape stereo speakers with Spatial Audio,
新 iPad Air 的横向立体声扬声器 支持空间音频
so it sounds great.
音效非常出色
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
And the 13-inch model has even better sound quality with double the bass.
而 13 英寸机型具备两倍低音效果 音质更棒
The new Air comes in four finishes:
新 iPad Air 有四款外观
a new Blue and a new Purple,
全新的蓝色和紫色
as well as a beautiful Starlight and Space Gray.
以及迷人的星光色和深空灰色
And its durable design uses a 100% recycled aluminum enclosure.
外壳采用 100% 再生铝金属，经久耐用
Air users also love how quickly they can get things done.
用户爱用 iPad Air 还因为它能快速处理任务
So we're stepping up performance in a big way
因此，我们大幅提升了它的性能
with the incredibly fast M2!
配备了超快的 M2！
M2 is a powerful chip that's improved in a number of ways over M1.
M2 这款超强的芯片 在多方面都超越了 M1
It has a faster CPU, faster GPU,
它拥有更快的 CPU 和 GPU
and much faster Neural Engine.
神经网络引擎更是大提速
And when combined with faster memory bandwidth,
加上更快的内存带宽
the new Air is nearly 50% faster than the previous Air with M1
新 iPad Air 比前代 M1 机型快了近 50%
for all types of productive and creative tasks.
胜任各类生产力和创造力任务
And compared to iPad Air with A14 Bionic,
相比配备 A14 仿生芯片的 iPad Air
the new Air provides up to an enormous
新 iPad Air 性能
three times faster performance.
最高跃升至原先三倍之多
So users can create faster than ever
用户可在 Affinity Designer 2 中
in Affinity Designer 2 to promote their business,
更快进行创作，以推广业务
and play graphically intensive games like the upcoming "Zenless Zone Zero,"
也可畅玩图形密集型游戏 如即将上线的《绝区零》
or the visually stunning "Assassin's Creed Mirage."
或画面酷炫的 Assassin's Creed Mirage
With M2, the new Air is also an incredibly powerful device for AI.
M2 的加持，还让新 iPad Air 化身为 实力超强的 AI 设备
It's blazing fast for powerful machine learning features in iPadOS,
能飞速运行 iPadOS 强大的机器学习功能
like Visual Look Up, Subject Lift, and Live Text capture.
如看图查询、主体提取和实况文本识别
Or for the ML Enhance tool in Photomator,
或在 Photomator 中使用 ML Enhance 工具
which uses AI models trained on over 20 million pro images
利用经两千万张专业图像训练的 AI 模型
to improve your photo with a single click.
来一键优化照片
We're thrilled to amp up performance with M2.
M2 带来的性能提升让我们非常期待
Amazing accessories expand what's possible on iPad Air.
众多精彩配件让 iPad Air 更加神通广大
The new Air works with the Magic Keyboard,
新 iPad Air 支持妙控键盘
with its built-in trackpad, backlit keys, and terrific floating design.
该键盘拥有内置触控板、背光按键 和绝妙的悬浮式设计
And of course, it supports the amazing Apple Pencil,
另外，它还支持强大的 Apple Pencil
so users can express their creative ideas in remarkable ways.
让出彩的创意得到出众的演绎
And with M2 under the hood,
有 M2 加身
the new Air supports Apple Pencil hover for greater precision,
新 iPad Air 支持 Apple Pencil 悬停 精准度再提升
letting you preview your mark before you make it.
让你在落笔前就能预览效果
So that's the new iPad Air,
以上就是全新 iPad Air
now available in 11-inch and 13-inch models,
现提供 11 英寸和 13 英寸机型
powered by the incredible M2 chip,
由 M2 芯片强势驱动
and featuring a landscape front camera and faster Wi-Fi.
配备横向前置摄像头、更快的无线网络连接
The new iPad Air is more powerful and versatile than ever.
新 iPad Air 比以往更强大、更多用
Now back to John.
镜头交还给 John
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
John: The new Air is awesome.
John：全新 iPad Air 非常棒
And both models feature double the starting storage,
两款机型起步的存储容量
which is now 128GB.
现在都翻倍至 128GB
We've also expanded the number of storage options
我们还提供更多存储容量选择
by adding 512GB and 1TB.
新增了 512GB 和 1TB 选项
And even with all these upgrades,
尽管有以上种种升级
we're thrilled that the new 11-inch Air still starts at just $599.
全新 11 英寸 iPad Air 起售价仅为 $599
And the 13-inch Air is just $799.
13 英寸机型起售价仅为 $799
That's a remarkable value for a device
如此超值的价格就能入手这款
with so many advanced features and capabilities.
拥有众多先进功能和本领的产品
You can order the new Air today, and it will be available next week.
全新 iPad Air 今日起即可订购 并将于下周发售
iPad Pro pioneers our most advanced technologies
iPad Pro 是我们尖端技术的先锋
and pushes the limits of what iPad can be.
不断突破着 iPad 的界限
And it empowers users to push the limits of their productivity
同时也在力挺用户突破生产力
and creativity as well.
和创造力的界限
Users like illustrators, who use Procreate to produce their next masterpiece.
插画师们用 Procreate 来创作一幅幅大作
And 3D designers using SketchUp to conceive their most ambitious projects.
3D 设计师用 SketchUp 来构思 雄心勃勃的大项目
Of course, it's not just for pros.
当然，它不只适合专业人士
iPad Pro is for anyone who wants the ultimate iPad experience.
iPad Pro 适合每个想获得终极 iPad 体验的人
It's the combination of the world's best displays,
出类拔萃的显示屏
the extraordinary performance of our latest M-series chips,
最新款 M 系列芯片的超强性能
and advanced connectivity and accessories,
先进的连接功能和配件
in an ultraportable design that puts iPad Pro in a class by itself.
再加上超便携的设计，让 iPad Pro 卓尔不群
Well today, we're not only going to push the limits of what you can do on iPad.
今天，我们不仅要突破 iPad 能力的界限
We're going to crush them!
还要粉碎这些界限！
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
This is the all-new, impossibly thin,
这就是全新的
incredibly powerful iPad Pro!
超薄超强悍的 iPad Pro！
It has a stunning new design,
拥有惊艳的新设计
breakthrough new display,
突破性的新显示屏
outrageous performance, and amazing accessories.
磅礴的性能和出色的配件
Let's get started with its stunning design.
我们先来看看它的惊艳设计
We've always envisioned iPad as a magical sheet of glass,
一直以来，我们对 iPad 的设想 就是一片充满魔力的玻璃
and with this new design, that vision is brought to life more than ever.
而新设计让这个想法的实现更近一步
The new Pro comes in two sizes:
新 iPad Pro 有两种尺寸
a new, super portable 11-inch model
超便携的全新 11 英寸机型
and a new, expansive 13-inch model.
以及更大的全新 13 英寸机型
And both are unbelievably thin.
两款机型都纤薄到不可思议
The 11-inch Pro is 5.3 mm thin.
11 英寸机型薄至 5.3 毫米
And the 13-inch Pro is an incredible 5.1 mm thin.
13 英寸机型更薄至 5.1 毫米
Compared to the previous iPad Pro, the difference is striking.
和前代 iPad Pro 比起来非常明显
The new iPad Pro is even thinner than the iPod nano,
新 iPad Pro 甚至比 iPod nano 还纤薄
which makes it the thinnest Apple product ever!
成就了最薄的 Apple 产品！
And they're both lighter as well.
它们也都更轻了
In fact, the 11-inch model is less than a pound
11 英寸机型重量不到 1 磅
and the 13-inch model is nearly a quarter pound lighter than its predecessor.
13 英寸机型也比前代轻了近四分之一磅
iPad Pro comes in two great finishes: Silver and Space Black,
iPad Pro 可选两种精美外观 银色和深空黑色
both with 100% recycled aluminum enclosures.
均采用 100% 再生铝金属外壳
And it's just as strong as the previous design,
机身虽然比前代更薄
despite being so much thinner.
坚固却丝毫不减
Just holding it in your hands is an unbelievable experience.
仅仅拿在手里，感觉就非同一般
Now let's talk about its breakthrough new display.
再来看看它突破性的新显示屏
With the new iPad Pro, we wanted to give customers
我们希望新 iPad Pro 带给用户
an even more remarkable visual experience.
更棒的观看体验
And we did just that by bringing OLED to iPad for the very first time.
为此，我们首次将 OLED 装备于 iPad
With OLED technology, the pixels generate both the light
OLED 技术可让像素同时产生光和色彩
and the color for unparalleled precision.
精准度非常出众
However, for the expansive displays in iPad Pro,
但 iPad Pro 屏幕很大
a single OLED panel doesn't generate enough brightness
单单一层 OLED 面板的亮度
to deliver the XDR performance iPad Pro users expect.
还无法达到 iPad Pro 用户 所期待的 XDR 性能
So we developed a state-of-the-art display that uses two OLED panels
因此，我们开发了 使用双层 OLED 面板的先进显示屏
and combines the light from both
通过两块面板一起发光
to deliver phenomenal full-screen brightness.
来实现出众的全屏亮度
This technology is called tandem OLED and it's a breakthrough for iPad Pro.
这项技术称为双层串联 OLED 是 iPad Pro 上的一大创举
The new Pro can support an incredible 1000 nits of full-screen brightness
新 iPad Pro 能以惊人的 1000 尼特全屏亮度
for both SDR and HDR content
呈现 SDR 和 HDR 内容
and 1600 nits of peak HDR brightness.
并能以 1600 尼特峰值亮度呈现 HDR 内容
No other device of its kind delivers this level of display quality.
屏幕显示水准堪称一枝独秀
And because tandem OLED technology enables sub-millisecond control
由于双层串联 OLED 技术能以亚毫秒级
over the color and luminance of each pixel,
来控制每个像素的色彩和亮度
the display in the new Pro takes XDR precision to a whole new level.
新 iPad Pro 的显示屏将 XDR 精准度 提升到了新的境界
Specular highlights in photos and video appear brighter.
照片和视频的亮部更明亮
Blacks are deeper and more true.
黑色更深邃、更真实
And there's more detail in shadows and low light than ever before on iPad.
暗部和低光下的细节呈现也胜过历代 iPad
And it's even more responsive to content in motion.
对动态内容的响应也更灵敏
Everything you view on this display will look amazing.
这块屏幕上的一切看着都很赞
And we're calling it the Ultra Retina XDR.
我们称它为超精视网膜 XDR 显示屏
And it's coming to both models!
而且两款机型都采用了它！
So now both sizes of iPad Pro feature our most advanced display technology.
两种尺寸的 iPad Pro 都具备我们最先进的显示技术
HDR images of the night sky with details in the shadows
夜空的 HDR 图片展现出细腻的暗部
and pinpoint bright stars are rendered with stunning precision.
并以惊人的精准度呈现出璀璨的繁星
Beautifully captured HDR photos of gorgeous landscapes
绚丽的 HDR 风景大片
look incredibly vibrant.
看起来分外鲜明生动
And getting drawn into a movie is a truly extraordinary experience.
用它来看电影更是妙不可言
It's like holding a cinema right in your hands.
仿佛将电影院搬到了你的手中
And this display not only delivers breakthrough visual quality,
这块显示屏不仅画质实现了突破
it's much thinner and lighter than the previous one,
还比上一代更薄、更轻
enabling the striking design of the new iPad Pro.
从而成就了新 iPad Pro 的惊艳设计
And for Pro users working in high-end, color-managed workflows,
对于处理高端色彩管理工作流程
or in the most demanding ambient lighting conditions,
或在极端光照下的专业用户来说
we're excited to bring a nano-texture glass option to iPad Pro
iPad Pro 首次可选配纳米纹理玻璃面板
for the very first time.
这绝对是个好消息
Nano-texture glass is precisely etched at a nanometer scale,
这种玻璃面板以纳米级技术精准蚀刻
maintaining image quality and contrast while scattering ambient light
可在保证画质和对比度的同时散射环境光
for even less glare.
以进一步减少眩光
With all these amazing features,
凭借这些出色的功能
the Ultra Retina XDR display is unquestionably
超精视网膜 XDR 屏无愧为
the world's most advanced display.
业内最先进的显示屏
Now, let's talk about performance.
现在我们来聊聊性能
iPad Pro has always used incredibly advanced Apple silicon.
iPad Pro 历来采用超先进的 Apple 芯片
With M2 in the current iPad Pro,
当前 iPad Pro 中的 M2
it already delivers class-leading performance.
就已经具备傲人的性能
For the new iPad Pro, you might expect
对于新 iPad Pro，你可能以为
that we would use the extremely powerful M3.
我们会采用超强的 M3
But this stunning design and breakthrough display
但考虑到它惊艳的设计和突破性的显示屏
required that we make the leap to the next generation of Apple silicon.
我们决定直接使用再跨一代的 Apple 芯片
And here it is.
请看
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
Introducing M4!
M4 登场！
That's right.
没错
while delivering a huge leap in performance.
性能也有巨大的飞跃
And to tell you more, here's Tim Millet.
有请 Tim Millet 为大家详解
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
Tim Millet: M4 represents another big step forward for Apple silicon.
Tim Millet：M4 是 Apple 芯片的又一次飞跃
To start, M4 is built on second-generation
首先，M4 基于第二代 3 纳米工艺打造
3 nanometer technology that's even more power efficient.
能效更出色
This was essential to deliver incredible performance
iPad Pro 设计如此轻盈纤薄 性能却如此出色
in the exceptionally thin and light design of iPad Pro.
它功不可没
And M4 also features an entirely new display engine
M4 还拥有全新的显示引擎
designed with pioneering technology that enables the stunning precision,
它采用开创性的技术精心设计
color, and brightness of the Ultra Retina XDR display.
为超精视网膜 XDR 屏带来惊人的 精准度、色彩和亮度
In addition, M4 brings phenomenal performance to the new Pro.
此外，M4 还让新 iPad Pro 有了 强悍的性能
It has a powerful new CPU
它拥有强劲的新 CPU
and builds upon the next-generation GPU architecture debuted on M3.
并基于 M3 上首秀的新一代 GPU 架构打造
The new CPU, with up to four performance cores
新 CPU 有最多达 4 个性能核心
and now with six efficiency cores,
现更有 6 个能效核心
all with next-generation ML accelerators,
均配备新一代机器学习加速器
delivers up to 50% faster CPU performance over M2 in the previous iPad Pro.
CPU 速度相比前代 iPad Pro 的 M2 提升最高达 50%
The next-generation 10-core GPU architecture
新一代 10 核 GPU 架构
includes powerful features like Dynamic Caching,
拥有动态缓存这类强大的功能
and brings hardware-accelerated mesh shading and ray tracing
并把支持硬件加速的网格着色和光线追踪
to iPad for the first time!
首度带到 iPad 上！
So games like "Diablo Immortal" look fantastic.
因此《暗黑破坏神：不朽》这类游戏的 画面绝了
And pro rendering apps like Octane will flat-out fly
Octane 等专业渲染 app 也能飞速运行
with up to four times faster performance than M2!
速度相比 M2 提升至最高 4 倍！
And we've added these architecture and performance improvements
而我们在提升架构和性能的同时
while maintaining our industry-leading performance per watt.
依然保持着傲人的性能功耗比
M4 can deliver the same performance as M2,
M4 仅用一半功耗
using just half the power!
就能提供与 M2 相同的性能！
That's a tremendous gain in performance per watt,
这在性能功耗比上是巨大的提升
and perfect for the thin and light design of the new Pro.
对新 iPad Pro 轻薄的设计也正合适
Now, when we compare it to the latest PC chip in a thin and light laptop,
现在，相比各款轻薄笔电的新一代 PC 芯片
M4 can deliver the same performance using just a quarter of the power!
M4 只需四分之一的功耗 就能提供相同的性能！
That's the amazing power-efficient performance lead
Apple 芯片的出色能效可见一斑
Another way Apple silicon leads the industry
Apple 芯片另一个傲人之处
is with the Neural Engine, which the industry calls an NPU.
是神经网络引擎，业界称为 NPU
The Neural Engine is an IP-block in the chip
神经网络引擎是芯片上的一个 IP 模块
dedicated to the acceleration of AI workloads.
专为各种 AI 工作加速
Now, while the chip industry is just starting
芯片行业现在才刚刚开始 为部分处理器加入 NPU
we've been including our industry-leading Neural Engine in our chip for years.
而 Apple 芯片早在多年前就配备了 尖端的神经网络引擎
And now with M4, we have our most powerful Neural Engine ever,
现在随 M4 而来的
capable of an astounding 38 trillion operations per second!
运算速度达到了惊人的每秒 38 万亿次！
That's a breathtaking 60 times faster
是我们 A11 仿生上 首个神经网络引擎的 60 倍
Together with next-generation ML accelerators in the CPU,
再加上 CPU 的新一代机器学习加速器
a high-performance GPU, and more memory bandwidth,
高性能 GPU 和更多的内存带宽
the Neural Engine makes M4 an outrageously powerful chip for AI.
神经网络引擎让 M4 成为了 胜任 AI 任务的超强芯片
It can do amazing things even faster,
用它工作起来更快了
like easily isolate a subject from its background in 4K video
比如要将 4K 视频中的目标对象 从背景中分离出来
with just a tap in Final Cut Pro.
只需在 Final Cut Pro 中轻点一下就好
In fact, with this level of performance, the Neural Engine in M4 is more powerful
M4 的神经网络引擎
than any neural processing unit in any AI PC today!
性能强到足以傲视当今的 AI PC
So that's M4.
以上就是 M4
It's built with cutting-edge technology that enables the breakthrough design
它以尖端技术打造 成就了新 iPad Pro 突破性的设计
and stunning display of the new Pro,
和惊艳的显示屏
and delivers a giant leap in performance.
还实现了性能的飞跃
With M4, iPad Pro widens its lead as the most powerful device of its kind.
M4 的加身，让 iPad Pro 进一步巩固了 它在业界独树一帜的地位
Now, back to John.
让我们请回 John
John: The new iPad Pro wouldn't even be possible without M4.
John：没有 M4 就没有新 iPad Pro
And despite its much thinner and lighter design,
尽管设计上更轻薄
we've also substantially improved its thermal performance.
散热性能依然大幅提升
By incorporating graphite sheets into the main housing
我们在主外壳中加入石墨片
and copper in the Apple logo,
在 Apple 标志中加入铜
we've been able to improve thermal performance by nearly 20%.
从而将整体的散热性能提升了近 20%
And the combination of this improved design
这些优化的设计
along with M4 means the new iPad Pro is up to four times faster
联手 M4，让新 iPad Pro 的速度
than the previous iPad Pro with M2
比前代 M2 机型提升至最高 4 倍
and up to an astounding 10 times faster than the original iPad Pro.
比初代机型更是提升至最高 10 倍
Now, bringing iPad Pro to life is iPadOS,
而为 iPad Pro 画龙点睛的则是 iPadOS
with a number of advanced features that empower pros to do even more on iPad.
它众多先进的功能 让专业人士能用 iPad 成就更多精彩
With Reference Mode, iPadOS can precisely match color requirements
参考模式让 iPadOS 能在调色时 精准匹配色彩
where accurate and consistent image quality are extremely critical.
这时，精准度和图像质量的一致性是关键
And Stage Manager support for multiple overlapping windows
台前调度功能可叠放多个窗口
and external displays allows advanced users to work with more apps at once.
并支持外接显示器 让高阶用户能同时使用更多 app
iPadOS also has advanced frameworks like Core ML
iPadOS 还拥有 Core ML 等先进框架
that make it easy for developers to tap into the Neural Engine
让开发者能轻松利用神经网络引擎
to deliver powerful AI features, right on device.
直接在设备上实现强大的 AI 功能
And users can find thousands of these powerful apps on the App Store.
这类功能强大的 app 在 App Store 中有数千个
Pro apps unleash the incredible capabilities of iPad Pro.
专业 app 将能充分发挥 iPad Pro 的能力
Apps like Shapr3D enable users to design in CAD with Apple Pencil.
Shapr3D 等 app 能让用户 以 Apple Pencil 进行 CAD 设计
Or ZBrush, which brings game-changing 3D modeling and sculpting.
ZBrush 则带来了颠覆性的 3D 建模和雕刻
Our own pro apps for iPad unleash the remarkable capabilities
我们为 iPad 打造的专业 app 也会让 iPad Pro 尽展所能
Final Cut Pro and Logic Pro launched on iPad last year
Final Cut Pro 和 Logic Pro 去年已在 iPad 上推出
and have given artists the ability to create in completely new ways.
为艺术家带来了全然一新的创作方式
And now, only a year later, both apps are getting huge updates.
而短短一年后的现在 这两款 app 都迎来了重要更新
Introducing Final Cut Pro and Logic Pro 2!
Final Cut Pro 和 Logic Pro 2 登场！
To tell you more, here's Will.
有请 Will 详细介绍
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
Will Hui: Final Cut Pro and Logic Pro for iPad
Will Hui：iPad 版 Final Cut Pro 和 Logic Pro
were redesigned from the ground up for touch,
以触控为出发点进行了全新设计
so seasoned Mac users extending their workflows
让经验丰富的 Mac 用户可以扩展工作流程
and next-generation iPad creators can get even closer to their content.
并让新一代 iPad 创作者更得心应手
And today we're unveiling amazing updates that take creativity to the next level.
而今天的重大更新 将让创造力再上新境界
Let's start with Final Cut Pro,
先看看 Final Cut Pro
which lets you record, edit,
专业视频的拍摄、剪辑、修片和分享 都能在 iPad 上用它搞定
With the new iPad Pro and M4, it absolutely screams,
全新 iPad Pro 和 M4 的加持下 它表现更棒了
with final rendering up to two times faster than M1!
最终渲染速度最高达 M1 的两倍！
The latest version introduces an incredible new feature
新版本推出了一项超赞的新功能
to speed up your shoot called Live Multicam.
来加快视频拍摄的进度 这就是实时多机位
It transforms your iPad into a multicam production studio
它让 iPad 变身为多机位制作工作室
and puts you in the director's chair.
让你稳坐导演席
Live Multicam enables filmmakers to connect and preview
实时多机位可让电影工作者
up to four cameras all at once, all in one place.
在一处同时连接和预览多达四台摄像机
Creators can remotely direct each video angle and dial in exposure,
创作者可以远程操控每个视频角度
white balance, focus, and more.
并调整曝光、白平衡、焦点等
To support Live Multicam, we created an entirely new app for iPhone and iPad.
为支持实时多机位 我们为 iPhone 和 iPad 打造了全新的 app
And we call it Final Cut Camera.
这就是 Final Cut Camera
Final Cut Camera allows users to easily connect multiple iPhones or iPads
它能让用户轻松连接多部 iPhone 或 iPad
to capture additional angles during a Live Multicam shoot
为实时多机位画面获取更多角度
or record professional videos with precise manual controls
或通过精准的手动操控来录制专业视频
as a free standalone app.
而且它还是免费的独立 app
Final Cut Pro automatically transfers and syncs each Live Multicam angle
Final Cut Pro 可自动传输和同步 每个实时多机位角度
so you can seamlessly move from production to editing!
让你从拍摄到剪辑无缝衔接！
New external project support now offers creators
新的外部项目支持功能可让创作者更灵活
the flexibility of editing projects directly off a drive,
利用 iPad Pro 飞快的雷雳接口
leveraging the fast Thunderbolt connection of iPad Pro.
直接连上外接硬盘就能做剪辑
Editing and finishing is incredible with M4,
M4 带来超强的剪辑和修片功能
with support for up to four times more streams of ProRes RAW than M1.
支持的 ProRes RAW 视频流数量 最高达 M1 的 4 倍
Color grade, apply multiple effects,
在调色、应用多个特效
and render graphically intense timelines even faster.
以及渲染图形密集型时间线时，速度更快
Your HDR content has never looked better!
HDR 内容看起来更惊艳！
Final Cut Pro 2 transforms iPad Pro into a more powerful production studio
Final Cut Pro 2 让 iPad Pro 变身为 更强大的制作工作室
and opens up entirely new video workflows.
开启了全新的视频工作流程
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
Logic Pro for iPad turns things up for music producers.
iPad 版 Logic Pro 为音乐制作人 带来了截然不同的体验
Designed for everyone from emerging to established artists,
为了让新人和达人都顺手
Logic Pro for iPad has delivered the entire studio experience
它以简单易用的触控方式
with the simplicity of touch.
提供了完整的音乐工作室体验
Logic Pro 2 is so exciting and it's smarter than ever.
而 Logic Pro 2 更智能了
Today, artists find the Drummer feature in Logic fantastic
音乐人们都知道 Logic 中的鼓手功能
for adding drum performances to any song.
为歌曲添加鼓声非常好用
Now Drummer is getting some new bandmates in a feature we call Session Players.
现在，新增的伴奏乐手功能 为鼓手带来了新伙伴
We're introducing an all-new Bass and Keyboard Player,
全新的“贝司手”和“键盘手”
and like Drummer, they're built using AI.
它们和鼓手一样，都由 AI 构建
Simple controls let you dial in the perfect performance.
通过简单的操控就能呈现出精彩表演
Next, let's talk about effects.
接着来看看特效
While ChromaVerb simulates beautiful acoustics,
尽管 ChromaVerb 可模拟优美的声学效果
producers today rely on hardware to infuse digital recordings with analog warmth.
但制作人如今还是更依赖硬件为数字录音 注入特有的质感
Now, we're packing all of that into Logic Pro
为了让 Logic Pro 将这些打包通收
with a new plug-in we call ChromaGlow.
我们推出了新插件 ChromaGlow
We used machine learning to model that sound in amazing detail.
我们利用机器学习技术为这种质感建模 细节令人惊叹
And with the power of M4, iPad Pro users can leverage it
iPad Pro 用户借助 M4 的强劲动力
across many tracks, just like a world-class recording studio.
可在多个音轨上应用这个效果 仿佛身处世界一流的录音棚
Finally, let's talk remixing.
最后我们来聊聊混音
When a producer wants to sample just drums or only vocals,
当制作人只想对鼓声或人声进行采样
but doesn't have the original tracks or stems,
但又没有原始音轨或分轨时
Logic Pro provides a great solution.
Logic Pro 提供了理想的解决方案
We call it Stem Splitter.
这就是大分轨拆分器
It takes any recording and quickly extracts four distinct parts
它能处理任何录音 从中快速提取出四个不同声部
for voice, bass, drums, and other instruments.
人声、贝司、鼓和其他乐器
And with the power of M4 it all happens on device, super fast,
有了 M4 的强劲动力 这一切都能直接在设备上飞快搞定
so you can get on with remixing your song.
让你把更多精力放到歌曲混音上
So that's Logic Pro 2,
这就是 Logic Pro 2
faster and more intelligent than ever.
比以往更快、更智能
Back to you, John.
镜头还给你，John
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
John: Another feature of iPad Pro
John：iPad Pro 上的 app 如此好用 还要归功于它出色的摄像头和麦克风
which enable users to shoot, edit, and share all on one device.
让你只用一部设备就能拍摄、剪辑和分享
When creating a project in Final Cut Pro,
在 Final Cut Pro 中创建项目时
users can capture detailed 4K ProRes video
用户可借助 1200 万像素后置摄像头
using the 12MP back camera
拍摄细腻的 4K ProRes 视频
and rich audio from four studio-quality mics.
用四个录音棚级麦克风 录制细节丰富的音频
iPad Pro also includes the LiDAR Scanner,
iPad Pro 还拥有激光雷达扫描仪
which makes AR experiences faster and more stable.
带来更快、更稳定的增强现实体验
And a new adaptive True Tone flash that makes document scanning
新的自适应原彩闪光灯
on the new Pro better than ever.
提升了新 iPad Pro 的文档扫描功能
We've all had the experience of trying to scan a document
我们都有过这样的经历
in certain lighting conditions where it's hard to avoid casting a shadow.
在某些光线下扫描文件时 很难避免投下阴影
The new Pro solves this problem.
新 iPad Pro 就能解决这个问题
It uses AI to automatically detect documents like forms and receipts.
它可借助 AI 自动识别表格和发票等文件
If shadows are in the way,
如果有阴影
it instantly takes multiple photos with the new, adaptive flash.
它会立即使用新的自适应闪光灯 拍摄多张照片
The frames are stitched together and the result is a dramatically better scan.
然后将多个帧拼接在一起 让扫描效果显著提升
And because this feature is built into iPadOS,
这是 iPadOS 内置的功能
it comes to the Camera app, Files, Notes, and third-party apps, too.
因此相机 app、文件、备忘录 和第三方 app 都可以用
Finally, we have big news for the front-facing camera.
最后，我们的前置摄像头也有重大更新
The 12MP Ultra Wide camera moves from the portrait to the landscape edge,
1200 万像素超广角摄像头 从纵边移到了横边
just like iPad Air.
就和 iPad Air 一样
This is also the new home for Face ID,
这个位置还有面容 ID
and a completely new charging and pairing system for Apple Pencil.
以及 Apple Pencil 全新的充电和配对系统
The amazing accessories that work with iPad Pro
让 iPad Pro 用途更多样的
make it even more versatile,
还有各款精彩配件
and we have exciting news here, too.
在这方面我们也有好消息
To complement the incredible thin and light design of the new iPad Pro,
为搭配新 iPad Pro 纤薄轻巧的设计
we're introducing an all-new Magic Keyboard.
我们全新推出了一款妙控键盘
This is the new Magic Keyboard for iPad Pro.
这就是专为 iPad Pro 打造的妙控键盘
It's been completely redesigned to be much thinner, and even lighter.
它设计一新，更薄更轻
Opening it reveals the magic floating design that users love.
打开即可展现大家赞不绝口的悬浮式设计
It comes in two colors that perfectly match the new Pro.
它有两种颜色可选 与新 iPad Pro 的外观绝配
And it's loaded with great new features.
还具备出色的新功能
First, it now includes a function row
它加入了一排功能键
for quick access to convenient controls like screen brightness.
可直达各种便捷的控制功能，如屏幕亮度
It also has a gorgeous aluminum palm rest
它还配备了精美的铝金属掌托
and a larger trackpad that's even more responsive
和更大的触控板
with haptic feedback.
响应更灵敏并带有触觉反馈
So the entire experience feels just like using a MacBook.
种种体验就像在用 MacBook 一样
The incredible new Magic Keyboard makes the new Pro more portable
超棒的新款妙控键盘让新 iPad Pro
Now let's talk about the most beloved accessory for iPad Pro.
再来聊聊 iPad Pro 配件中的万人迷
And that's Apple Pencil.
Apple Pencil
Apple Pencil has been a game-changer
这款颠覆性的产品
for users to express their ideas and creativity.
可让用户尽情挥洒创意
It's loaded with all these advanced features that are simply a joy to use.
它配备了各项先进功能 用起来让人乐在其中
Today, we're introducing an entirely new Apple Pencil.
今天，我们带来了一款 全然一新的 Apple Pencil
And here it is!
请欣赏！
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
Introducing, Apple Pencil Pro.
Apple Pencil Pro 登场
It takes the Pencil experience to a whole new level.
它将 Apple Pencil 的体验提升至全新境界
And to tell you more, here's Leslie.
有请 Leslie 为大家详解
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
Leslie Ikemoto: Today, we're giving all those users who love Apple Pencil
Leslie Ikemoto：今天，我们为所有 喜爱 Apple Pencil 的用户
even more magical capabilities.
带来了更多巧妙的功能
To start we added a new sensor in the barrel of the Pencil
我们为 Apple Pencil 笔身 新增了一个传感器
to enable new interactions.
实现了全新的交互
So now, for example,
比如，现在只需轻捏笔身
you can just squeeze it to bring up a new tool palette.
即可打开新的工具盘
And when you squeeze the Pencil,
当你轻捏 Apple Pencil 时
a haptic engine delivers precise feedback that you can feel.
触觉引擎能给你精准的触觉反馈
A gyroscope allows you to roll the Pencil
陀螺仪让你可通过侧旋笔身
for precise control of the tool you're using,
来精准控制当前使用的工具
like changing the orientation of a shaped pen or brush.
比如调整笔头和笔刷工具的方向
If you ever lose Apple Pencil Pro,
如果你的 Apple Pencil Pro 丢失了
you can easily locate it since it now supports Find My.
也能被轻松定位，因为它支持查找功能
And of course, it pairs, charges, and stores magnetically
另外，它通过磁力吸附于 iPad Pro 侧面
on the side of iPad Pro.
并进行配对和充电
With all these new features,
有了这些新功能
Apple Pencil Pro allows you to bring your ideas to life like never before.
Apple Pencil Pro 为你带来了 实现创意的新方式
And developers can also create their own custom interactions.
开发者也能对交互进行自定
Here's James Cuda, the CEO of Procreate,
下面有请 Procreate 的 CEO James Cuda
to show you some of the amazing things they're doing with Apple Pencil Pro.
展现他们用 Apple Pencil Pro 所做的一些精彩实例
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
James Cuda: We believe art is for everyone.
James Cuda：我们相信人人都有艺术细胞
The desire to create is part of what makes us human.
创造欲是人类与生俱来的天性
The day the iPad was announced, we founded Procreate,
在 iPad 发布的当天，我们创立了 Procreate
because we could see its incredible potential for creativity.
因为我们看到 iPad 在激发创造力方面的巨大潜能
Apple Pencil was a breakthrough for artists.
Apple Pencil 对艺术家而言是突破性的工具
And now Apple Pencil Pro completely transforms
现在，Apple Pencil Pro 让 Procreate 中的绘画体验全然一新
With barrel roll, we can create brushes that respond in entirely new ways.
有了侧旋功能 我们可以创建以全新方式响应的画笔
Artists can roll to automatically change size,
创作者可通过旋转笔身
introduce color, and much more.
来自动改变尺寸、引入颜色等
With Apple Pencil squeeze,
利用 Apple Pencil 轻捏手势
you can target actions without even touching the screen.
即使不碰屏幕也能执行操作
You can activate shortcuts with all your favorite brushes and tools.
还能为常用的画笔和工具激活快捷方式
Or you can hover over your canvas and simply squeeze
你也可将笔身悬停于画布之上
to select the layer that you wish to work on,
然后轻捏以选择想要操作的图层 来加速浏览
speeding up navigation on even the most complex projects.
即使项目非常复杂也没关系
And when you're moving or transforming objects on your canvas,
当你移动或变换画布上的对象时
haptic feedback gives you the confidence
触觉反馈能让你确信这些对象已精准就位
These new devices are amazing for drawing and painting in Procreate,
在 Procreate 中绘图作画时 这些新设备非常好用
and we can really take advantage of all that precision and performance
而当我们用 Procreate Dreams 制作动画时
when we're ready to animate in Procreate Dreams.
它们的精准度和性能会大有用武之地
In Procreate Dreams, we've taken barrel roll even further.
我们在 Procreate Dreams 中 让侧旋功能更进一步
With Performing, you can create animations
借助演出实录功能
by recording your actions while the movie plays.
你可以在播放视频时录制你的动作 以此来生成动画
Now, you can move and rotate your object at the same time
现在，你可以同时移动和旋转对象
and really stay in the moment.
带入感十足
And thanks to all the power of M4,
得益于 M4 的强劲动力
we're able to introduce new, computationally intense effects,
我们推出了需要高强度运算的新特效
like Lens Blur,
比如 Lens Blur
for creating realistic bokeh, and camera focus animations.
来制作逼真的背景虚化效果 和镜头对焦过程的动画
On this new iPad Pro, we're seeing a 50% improvement in performance,
全新 iPad Pro 性能提升了 50%
unlocking capability that was just not possible before.
解锁了许多以前无法实现的功能
Hundreds of tracks and all of your changes happening in real time.
例如即时完成对数百条轨道的修改
Incredible advancements like these inspire us
这些显著的进步
Back to Leslie.
镜头交还给 Leslie
Leslie: The new version of Procreate looks amazing,
Leslie：新版 Procreate 太强了
and we can't wait to see all the other apps
我们也很期待看到其他 app
that will take advantage of these powerful new capabilities.
如何充分利用这些强大的新功能
So that's the new Apple Pencil Pro.
以上就是全新 Apple Pencil Pro
With its incredible new features, it begins a whole new era
凭借众多精彩新功能
Now, back to John.
再次有请 John
John: The new features in Apple Pencil Pro are simply revolutionary.
John：Apple Pencil Pro 的新功能是开创性的
And we're also excited that Apple Pencil Pro works
而且 Apple Pencil Pro 还适用于 全新 iPad Air
giving Air users yet another pro feature to push their creativity.
让这些用户也可借助专业功能 尽情发挥创造力
That means Air and Pro users have two Pencil models to choose from.
这意味着 iPad Air 和 iPad Pro 用户 将有两款 Apple Pencil 可选
So that's the new iPad Pro.
这就是全新 iPad Pro
It features the breakthrough Ultra Retina XDR display,
拥有突破性的超精视网膜 XDR 屏
the next-level performance of M4,
M4 跨代的性能
fast 5G cellular, and a landscape front-facing camera,
高速 5G 蜂窝网络 以及横向前置摄像头
all in a jaw-dropping, incredibly thin and light design
并将这一切融于惊人的轻薄设计中
that's the thinnest Apple product ever.
成就了最薄 Apple 产品
This is the iPad we've always dreamed of making.
这是我们一直以来梦想中的 iPad
The new iPad Pro comes with double the storage, which is now 256GB.
全新 iPad Pro 起步存储容量翻倍至 256GB
The 11-inch model starts at $999,
11 英寸机型起售价 $999
and the 13-inch model starts at $1299.
13 英寸机型起售价 $1299
The new Magic Keyboard for iPad Pro is $299 and $349.
适用于 iPadPro 的全新妙控键盘 售价 $299 和 $349
And the new Apple Pencil Pro is just $129,
全新 Apple Pencil Pro 售价仅 $129
an amazing value for such an incredible device.
对于如此出色的设备来说，非常超值
Customers can order the new iPad Pro, Magic Keyboard,
全新 iPad Pro、妙控键盘
and Apple Pencil Pro today and they'll be available next week.
和 Apple Pencil Pro 今日起可订购 下周发售
Today we're also making iPad (10th generation) even more affordable.
iPad (第十代) 现在也更超值
It's now just $349.
起售价仅为 $349
Making it a great entry point into the iPad lineup.
是 iPad 产品系列的理想入门机型
We couldn't be more excited about today's announcements.
今天的发布让我们无比激动
They take iPad further than ever.
它们让 iPad 大步飞跃
Now, back to Tim.
再次有请 Tim
♪ ♪
♪ ♪
Tim: We're so excited about this new iPad lineup.
Tim：我们很高兴推出新的 iPad 系列产品
A more affordable entry-level iPad with an all-screen design.
采用全面屏设计、价格更超值的入门款 iPad
The new iPad Air available for the first time in two sizes.
首次提供两个尺寸的全新 iPad Air
The remarkably thin and powerful all-new iPad Pro.
超纤薄、超强悍的全新 iPad Pro
And of course the small but mighty iPad mini.
当然，还有身形小巧但本领非凡的 iPad mini
This is the strongest iPad lineup we've ever had!
这是我们迄今最强大的 iPad 阵容
It's the best in the industry, by far.
堪称实力超群
With these new iPads and the introduction of the powerful M4 chip,
随着这些新款 iPad、强势登场的 M4 芯片
the big upgrades to Final Cut Pro and Logic Pro for iPad,
重大升级的 iPad 版 Final Cut Pro 和 Logic Pro
along with the new Apple Pencil Pro and new Magic Keyboard,
以及全新 Apple Pencil Pro 和妙控键盘的亮相
it truly is the biggest day for iPad since its introduction.
今天不愧为 iPad 问世以来的又一个里程碑
From consumers to pros,
无论是普通用户还是专业大咖
iPad enables people to take their ideas,
iPad 都能帮助他们激发灵感，挥洒创意
We can't wait to see what users do with these incredible new iPads.
我们迫不及待想看到 这些新 iPad 如何助用户们大显身手
And we look forward to seeing you next month at WWDC,
期待下个月 WWDC 再见
where we'll talk about the future of our platforms,
届时我们将探讨 Apple 各个平台的未来
and share some exciting details about what's to come.
并将有一系列精彩分享
Thank you for joining us.
感谢大家的参与
Have a great day!
祝开心！